<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>教程 | Elizaveta E. Parfenova</title>
    <link>https://parfenovaee.github.io/category/%E6%95%99%E7%A8%8B/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://parfenovaee.github.io/category/%E6%95%99%E7%A8%8B/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>教程</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 13:50:44 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://parfenovaee.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>教程</title>
      <link>https://parfenovaee.github.io/category/%E6%95%99%E7%A8%8B/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming languages</title>
      <link>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/language/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 13:50:44 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/language/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a huge number of directions in IT: from creating games and applications to developing robots that completely replace human labor. There is no programming language that is equally fast at solving problems in any of these areas. So it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand that any lists of the best programming languages are subjective and usually based on how popular, versatile, and comfortable the language is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are programming languages?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where are programming languages used?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The top 5 programming languages currently in use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**What are programming languages?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A programming language is a set of formal rules by which programs are written. A normal language is needed to communicate with people, but a programming language is needed to communicate with a computer. Like any natural language, it has a vocabulary - words, functions and operators - from which expressions are composed according to syntax rules. They have a clear, well-defined meaning, understandable to a computer - semantics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Where are programming languages used?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The uses of programming languages are very different. They depend on the area where the user wants to use them. For each area, there are &amp;ldquo;different&amp;rdquo; programming languages. Generally speaking, programming languages are used in web programming, game development, android development, Operating Systems development, software development, neural networks and data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Top 5 programming languages currently&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1. JavaScript language&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   Don&#39;t confuse it with Java - they are different and totally different languages.
   JavaScript is used for graphics, mobile and web applications, and browser-based operating systems. It&#39;s very versatile and easy to learn.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2. The Python language&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   Python is easy to learn and is often used to teach children programming, such as at the Skysmart online school. Python programs are close to a natural language, so it&#39;s great as a first language for a beginning programmer.
   It is a very common language and a large number of projects have been implemented in it. Python is used extensively at Google and much of the source code for YouTube is written in it. It&#39;s also often used in creating robot machines.
   The strengths of Python are its modularity and its ability to integrate with other languages, while the downsides are its slow speed and high memory consumption.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;3. Java language&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   A general-purpose programming language that consistently ranks high in popularity ratings. Applications in Java can run on any computer, for this purpose a virtual Java-machine is created. Mobile applications for the Android operating system are actively being developed in Java.
   Successful projects such as RuneScape, Yahoo, Amazon, eBay and LinkedIn are written in Java.
   Disadvantages of Java are slow programs and high RAM consumption.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;4. C# language&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   The name of the language reads &amp;quot;C Sharp&amp;quot;. It was developed in 1998-2001 within Microsoft for creating applications.
   C# belongs to the family of languages with C-like syntax, of which it is closest to C++ and Java. That is why C# has a rather complex syntax, which is considered a disadvantage.
   Compared to C and C++, C# has safe code. C# is dozens of times slower than C.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*5. rnr language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   Widely used for creating web applications, leading in applications for creating dynamic websites. PHP has undergone a rapid evolution and has become popular among programmers. However, it is often criticized by programmers for its inconsistent syntax.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, programming languages are very diverse and exist as long as the purposes for which they are used are relevant. There are now thousands of programming languages used for their purposes, with a large number of people working on them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My fifth week</title>
      <link>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 13:50:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/weeks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another week has come to an end. Summer is finally here. This week I finished the last Labs on Operating Systems. These are labs #13 and #14. I also did some rather difficult tasks in Python. Let&amp;rsquo;s talk a little more about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laboratory work №13&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of the laboratory work was to obtain the simplest skills in developing, analyzing, testing and debugging applications in UNIX/Linux OS on the example of creating a calculator with simple functions in C programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this work, I created a rudimentary calculator and worked with it using the gdb debugger. It was quite interesting and informative and improved my skills with the console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laboratory Work №14&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this lab work was to gain practical skills working with named channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the course of the work we learned how to run servers. I can&amp;rsquo;t say that this work was easy, but the main difficulty was not in launching channels, but in pre-writing files. But after carefully studying the theory, I managed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Python this week, I learned how to build charts and histograms, which caused a little difficulty. I also wrote a program to read strings from a file and convert them into a dictionary. I found this task to be the most challenging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So last week was quite productive and taught me a lot of new things in programming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific programming languages</title>
      <link>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 21:52:25 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article we will talk about scientific programming and what languages are best for science work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is scientific programming?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where is scientific programming used
The languages of scientific programming
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Julia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**What is scientific programming?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Science programming&lt;/em&gt; is a highly oriented programming style for scientific calculations. It is distinguished from other types of programming by the ultimate correctness and stability of the final product, strict separation of scientific and interface parts, individuality of algorithms, and prevalence of efficiency over universality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Where is scientific programming applied?
 
Scientific programming is at the heart of all modern global research. All advanced technologies, from quantum computers to space programs, would not be possible without experts in science programming who can provide scientists with a reliable and accurate tool for making discoveries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of fields of science are directly dependent on the level of development of scientific programming. For example, unmanned vehicles, &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; systems of urban and agricultural management, stock exchanges; robotics, genetic engineering, artificial intelligence, surpassing human capabilities, are waiting for their fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scientific programming languages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different fields may use different existing programming languages, but in this article I want to talk about three.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1. R&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R, which is a direct descendant of the older S programming language, was released way back in 1995 and has been getting better and better ever since. Written in languages such as C and Fortran, it is now supported by the R Foundation for Statistical Computing. An excellent set of high-quality, open-source, subject-oriented packages. R has packages available for almost every quantitative and statistical application imaginable. This includes neural networks, nonlinear regression, phylogenetics, building complex charts, graphs, and much, much more. Along with the basic setup, we are given the option to install extensive built-in functions and methods as an add-on. R is a powerful language with a huge variety of statistical and visualization applications and its open source nature has gathered a large following of developers. It is because of its effectiveness for initial purposes that this programming language has been able to achieve widespread popularity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2. Python&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is one of the most popular programming languages at the moment. It has a simple syntax and a variety of different libraries and frameworks to help achieve the desired task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is a good option for data science purposes, and this is true for both entry-level and advanced data science jobs. Much of data science is centered around the ETL (extract-transform-load) process. This feature makes Python an ideal programming language for such purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*3. Julia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released just over 5 years ago, Julia impressed the world of computational methods. The language achieved such popularity because several large organizations, including some in the financial industry, almost immediately began using it for their purposes. Julia is a compiled JIT (&amp;ldquo;just-in-time&amp;rdquo;) language that achieves good performance. It is a fairly simple language, with dynamic typing and scripting capabilities of an interpreted language such as Python. Julia was designed to do numerical analysis, it can also be considered as a general-purpose programming language. Of course, this language has its shortcomings, the main one being its youth. This language doesn&amp;rsquo;t have enough software packages yet, but in a few years it will be able to compete with its main competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific programming and the languages with which it can be handled are gaining unprecedented popularity because of the progress that is being made in our society. It allows scientists to advance technology and transform our world into the &amp;ldquo;world of the future.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My fours week</title>
      <link>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 21:52:12 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/week4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My week was full and productive. I did several labs (this time there were more than usual), two of which were on Operating Systems. These were labs #11 and #12. Let&amp;rsquo;s talk a little bit about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lab work №11&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the work was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn the basics of UNIX shell programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn how to write more complex command files using logical control structures and loops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab work was quite complicated, so it took a long time to complete. During it I wrote 4 command files designed to perform different tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laboratory Work №12&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the work was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn the basics of UNIX shell programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn how to write more complex command files using logical control structures and loops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this lab work, I wrote three command files, one of which implemented the man command. I also learned how to use the built-in RANDOM variable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very interesting was the Lab work on mathematical modeling, where we program in Python. It took me quite a long time, but I got it done, correcting errors that appeared along the way. During the course of the work, I learned quite a few new functions and methods, as well as new approaches to solving problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, over the past week I have improved my shell programming skills, as well as learned much more about Python syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My third week</title>
      <link>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 23:17:26 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/week3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This past week has been a productive one. I did several labs again, two of which were steadily on Operating Systems. These were labs #9 and #10. Let me tell you a little bit about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laboratory Work №9&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the lab work was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To get acquainted with the operating system Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To get practical skills in working with the Emacs editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this laboratory work I was introduced to a fairly complex but interesting editor Emacs. I learned how to work with windows and buffers as well as how to edit text using keyboard shortcuts. I liked this editor more than the ones I had previously learned about, because of the variety of its functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laboratory Work №10&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the laboratory work was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To learn the basics of UNIX/Linux shell programming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To learn how to write small command files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab work was the first in the course where we started programming. It introduced me to the command shell. Through it I learned how to write small scripts that make it easier for the user to work with the operating system. This work was quite interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still continuing to learn Python in my mathematical modeling course and doing labs on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little bit about the good stuff. Being active outside, especially when the weather is there, is a wonderful thing. You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t forget about it. Especially if with company. Especially if it&amp;rsquo;s a favorite activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this past week I have been familiarizing myself with the new text editor, writing a few small team files, continuing to program in Python, and remembering to have a good rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Translated with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.DeepL.com/Translator&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.DeepL.com/Translator&lt;/a&gt; (free version)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report formatting</title>
      <link>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 23:12:07 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article you will learn how to properly draw reports. Get acquainted with the structure and rules of screenshot design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Report and Structure
2. Components of the report
3. How to design screenshots&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Report and its structure&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Report&lt;/em&gt; - message, report about your actions, work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report must contain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;title page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;work purpose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;work progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conclusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the specifics of the report, it may also contain a theoretical introduction, an answer to the control questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report can be made in any text editor that is available to you. For example, the classic Word or LibreOffice. I am currently doing reports in a Markdown editor, so this is also quite possible. The key is to understand the objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Components of the report&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A cover page.&lt;/em&gt; Should contain information about the name of the job for which the report is being written and the person who did the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose of the work.&lt;/em&gt; This section obviously spells out the purpose (or purposes) of the work that was planned to be achieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Task.&lt;/em&gt; Under this subheading, the task that was to be performed is written. Alternatively, the assignment is written in the course of the work next to each of the numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*This is the main section of the report. It describes each step by step, carried out in the course of the work. To each of the selected steps attached a screenshot, which clearly shows and proves the performance of the work. This section may also contain other elements, based again on the specifics of the report. For example, program listings, circuit diagrams, inserts from articles, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conclusion.* This section concludes the report and contains the result of the work performed. Usually the conclusion coincides with the goals of the work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The rules of screenshot design&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to know how to attach a screenshot to the report correctly. This cannot be done thoughtlessly by simply inserting a picture into the document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, in the text of the report you need to specify a link to the required image, i.e. sign the number next to the required sentence. After that, you need to insert a screenshot itself and be sure to write it. The caption includes the number of the figure (was specified earlier) and its title, corresponding to what is happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article we got acquainted with the concept of &amp;ldquo;report&amp;rdquo;, its structure and design rules.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markup language Markdown</title>
      <link>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 14:49:49 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article will give you a brief introduction to the Markdown lightweight markup language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is Markdown and how did it come about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reasons to use Markdown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**What is Markdown and how did it appear?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown is a lightweight markup language designed to denote formatting in plain text, with maximum human readability, and suitable for machine translation into languages for advanced publishing. (e.g. HTML) Originally created by John Gruber and Aaron Schwartz in 2004, whose goal was to create a lightweight markup language that was as readable and publishable as possible. The first Markdown implementation was written by Gruber, in Perl, but a number of third-party implementations have since appeared&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** Reasons to use Markdown**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to write text without frills, you can quickly get your docs ready for publication without any complicated layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a blog or website to host texts with a concise design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beautiful messages on WhatsApp or Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;writing documentation for your project on GitHub.
All of these cases have one thing in common - to make a minimal text layout so that it looks neat and can be read without special programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown Syntax&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section will give you a quick tutorial on how to use Markdown but not all the examples you will find here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown headings use a grid. They have five levels (five dimensions). One grid is level one (the largest heading); five grids are five levels (the smallest heading).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can select words or text with an asterisk (*).One asterisk on each side of the word (text) to be selected is italicized; Two asterisks are bold; Three asterisks are bold italicized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To cross out the text, you must put two squiggles (~) next to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numbered lists are done with numbers and a dot, and the numbers do not have to be put in order. That is even if you put 1, 5, 10, the list will end up with numbers in order. To make a bulleted list, you need to put a dash. Internal lists are made with the help of two &amp;ldquo;Tab&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blocks of citations are created using the symbol &amp;ldquo;&amp;gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To insert a link, you need this syntax:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[hyperlink text](the URL or filename to which the link is given)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A picture can be inserted like this, but with an exclamation mark:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;![Figure name](link to image)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Markdown markup language is very useful when the user needs to quickly produce concise text. Its syntax is very simple and you won&amp;rsquo;t need much time to learn it&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My second week</title>
      <link>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/%D0%BC%D0%BE%D1%8F-2-%D0%BD%D0%B5%D0%B4%D0%B5%D0%BB%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 14:49:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/%D0%BC%D0%BE%D1%8F-2-%D0%BD%D0%B5%D0%B4%D0%B5%D0%BB%D1%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did not notice how this week passed. This time I decided not to delay delivery of the Labs, so I started doing them at the weekend. As a result, at the moment, I did Labs 7 and 8 on Operating Systems and two Labs in C++. I can&amp;rsquo;t say it caused me much difficulty, but it did take some work. Let&amp;rsquo;s talk a little bit about the lab projects on Operating Systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laboratory work №7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the lab work was to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mastering the basic features of the Midnight Commander command shell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;acquiring practical skills in browsing and manipulating directories and files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the course of this work I became well acquainted with Midnight Commander. I studied its structure and menus and performed many operations using only the control keys. The second assignment of the laboratory work taught me how to work with the text editor mc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laboratory work №8&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the lab work was to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to get acquainted with the Linux operating system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get practical skills in working with the editor vi, which is installed by default in almost all distributions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This laboratory work taught me how to use the text editor vi and introduced me to its main modes and how to use them. Thanks to it I learned the basic hotkeys for performing many editing operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, over the past week I have learned to use the Midnight Commander shell and the common editor vi, and learned how to perform various operations with them. I continued to develop in C++ programming and did not forget about recreation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version control. Git</title>
      <link>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 19:55:31 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post will introduce you to the term &amp;ldquo;version control system&amp;rdquo;. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn about git, how it works, and what you need to do to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contents&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is a version control system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where version control systems are used
What git is and how it works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with Git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A critique of git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**What is a version control system?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A version control system (also defined as &amp;ldquo;version control system&amp;rdquo;, from Version Control System, VCS or Revision Control System) is software to facilitate working with changing information. Version control system allows you to store several versions of the same document, to return to earlier versions if necessary, to find out who made this or that change and many other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Where are version control systems used?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such systems are most commonly used in software development to store the source code of the program being developed. However, they can also be successfully applied in other areas where large numbers of continuously changing electronic documents are handled. In particular, version control systems are used in Computer Aided Design Systems, usually as part of Product Data Management (PDM) systems. Version control is used in Software Configuration Management Tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**What is git and how does it work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git is the absolute leader in popularity among modern version control systems. It is a developed project with active support and open source. The git system was originally developed in 2005 by Linus Torvalds - the creator of the Linux operating system kernel. Git is used for version control in a huge number of software development projects, both commercial and open source. The system is used by many professional software developers. It works perfectly on different operating systems and can be used with many integrated development environments (IDEs).
Version control allows you to see changes at any stage of development and go back to any point.  But that&amp;rsquo;s not quite the case. Changes are saved as commits. In Russian, it&amp;rsquo;s a commit. You make an initial commit to save the initial state of the project, and then for each change. This works like a snapshot of the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, git allows you to send data to a remote server. Not only the finished version is sent, but all of the snapshots are sent, so anyone on the team can see the history of changes. Each snapshot should have a comment, so it&amp;rsquo;s easier to work with git and make it easier to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Development in git is focused on providing high performance, security and flexibility of the distributed system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working with git&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting started with git requires a few steps.  First, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to create a GitHub account.  Next, set up and configure any features and options you may need via a terminal. The next step is to create a remote repository (or clone it) and connect the system to it. Basically, git is ready to go. You can move the files you need locally (on the system) to the correct directories and write commands that coordinate the local repository. The commands are: - git add .  - save changes to the current directory; -git commut - explain changes; - git push - send to the central repository. There is one other command that is better to run before the previous three. This is the git pull command, which loads changes made by someone else (or from another system).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git has often been criticized for being difficult to learn because some terms may be unfamiliar to newcomers and others may have different meanings. This being said, git is a very powerful system and offers many great features. It will take some time to learn, but the skills learned will help team members work much faster.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first week</title>
      <link>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/%D0%BC%D0%BE%D1%8F-1-%D0%BD%D0%B5%D0%B4%D0%B5%D0%BB%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 19:49:46 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/%D0%BC%D0%BE%D1%8F-1-%D0%BD%D0%B5%D0%B4%D0%B5%D0%BB%D1%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My week was full and productive. In addition to satisfying my personal interests in general, I did four labs, two of which were on Operating Systems. These were labs #5 and #6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lab Work №5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lab work was called &amp;ldquo;Analyzing the Linux File System. Commands for working with files and directories&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its purpose was to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To get acquainted with the Linux file system, its structure, names and contents of directories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To gain practical skills in using commands to work with files and directories, managing processes (and jobs), checking disk usage, and maintaining the file system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this work, I studied the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mv&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; commands in detail, remembered the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;touch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mkdir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; commands. I also learned what permissions are and how to modify them with the command chmod. Using the man command I learned more about the thermal commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laboratory Work №6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The topic of the next lab work was &amp;ldquo;Finding Files. Redirecting I/O. View running processes&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purpose of work: getting acquainted with the tools of file search and text data filtering. Gaining practical skills: on managing processes (and tasks), checking disk usage and maintaining file systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lab work helped me learn about I/O streams and how to handle them (for example, redirecting the standard output stream (ls) to the file I needed). Also I learnt how to use the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;find&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;grep&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; commands, to run background processes, to get information about them and to eliminate them with the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kill&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, during the last week, I have continued to learn C++ programming language and started to learn a new one which I have never worked with before - Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, during the past week I have learned different Linux terminal commands that allow me to work with files and continued to develop my programming skills.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Wowchemy, the website builder for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parfenovaee.github.io/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Wowchemy website builder for Hugo, along with its starter templates, is designed for professional creators, educators, and teams/organizations - although it can be used to create any kind of site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The template can be modified and customised to suit your needs. It&amp;rsquo;s a good platform for anyone looking to take control of their data and online identity whilst having the convenience to start off with a &lt;strong&gt;no-code solution (write in Markdown and customize with YAML parameters)&lt;/strong&gt; and having &lt;strong&gt;flexibility to later add even deeper personalization with HTML and CSS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can work with all your favourite tools and apps with hundreds of plugins and integrations to speed up your workflows, interact with your readers, and much more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-template-is-mobile-first-with-a-responsive-design-to-ensure-that-your-site-looks-stunning-on-every-device&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;The template is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      The template is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-started&#34;&gt;Get Started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👉 &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/templates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a new site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📚 &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personalize your site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💬 &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chat with the &lt;strong&gt;Wowchemy community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugo community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🐦 Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wowchemy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GeorgeCushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@GeorgeCushen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23MadeWithWowchemy&amp;amp;src=typed_query&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;#MadeWithWowchemy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💡 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Request a &lt;strong&gt;feature&lt;/strong&gt; or report a &lt;strong&gt;bug&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;em&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⬆️ &lt;strong&gt;Updating Wowchemy?&lt;/strong&gt; View the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/hugo-tutorials/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Update Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crowd-funded-open-source-software&#34;&gt;Crowd-funded open-source software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help us develop this template and software sustainably under the MIT license, we ask all individuals and businesses that use it to help support its ongoing maintenance and development via sponsorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-click-here-to-become-a-sponsor-and-help-support-wowchemys-future-httpswowchemycomplans&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/plans/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;❤️ Click here to become a sponsor and help support Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s future ❤️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a token of appreciation for sponsoring, you can &lt;strong&gt;unlock &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/plans/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; awesome rewards and extra features 🦄✨&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecosystem&#34;&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/hugo-academic-cli&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hugo Academic CLI&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Automatically import publications from BibTeX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Check out the latest &lt;strong&gt;demo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/user-stories/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;view the &lt;strong&gt;showcase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of personal, project, and business sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page builder&lt;/strong&gt; - Create &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/page-builder/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;widgets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;elements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit any type of content&lt;/strong&gt; - Blog posts, publications, talks, slides, projects, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create content&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/import/jupyter/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jupyter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/install-locally/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RStudio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugin System&lt;/strong&gt; - Fully customizable &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/customization/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;color&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font themes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display Code and Math&lt;/strong&gt; - Code highlighting and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LaTeX math&lt;/a&gt; supported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrations&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disqus commenting&lt;/a&gt;, Maps, Contact Forms, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beautiful Site&lt;/strong&gt; - Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry-Leading SEO&lt;/strong&gt; - Help get your website found on search engines and social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Galleries&lt;/strong&gt; - Display your images and videos with captions in a customizable gallery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile Friendly&lt;/strong&gt; - Look amazing on every screen with a mobile friendly version of your site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-language&lt;/strong&gt; - 34+ language packs including English, 中文, and Português&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-user&lt;/strong&gt; - Each author gets their own profile page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Pack&lt;/strong&gt; - Assists with GDPR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stand Out&lt;/strong&gt; - Bring your site to life with animation, parallax backgrounds, and scroll effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-Click Deployment&lt;/strong&gt; - No servers. No databases. Only files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wowchemy and its templates come with &lt;strong&gt;automatic day (light) and night (dark) mode&lt;/strong&gt; built-in. Alternatively, visitors can choose their preferred mode - click the moon icon in the top right of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt; to see it in action! Day/night mode can also be disabled by the site admin in &lt;code&gt;params.toml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/customization&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Choose a stunning &lt;strong&gt;theme&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for your site. Themes are fully customizable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-present &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
